Guide to the Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College circa 1955 - circa 1956
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College
circa 1955 - circa 1956
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu
P 164
Smith-Western Inc.
0.1 cubic foot, including 89 photographs 1 box
The Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College contain images of Oregon State College campus buildings and sorority and fraternity houses. These images were likely printed as post cards and sold in the College bookstore. Smith-Western Company was established in 1947 as a manufacturer of souvenir paper goods and operates today as a supplier for the tourist and attraction industries.
Historical Note:
Based out of Tacoma, Washington, Smith-Western Company was founded in 1947 as a manufacturer of souvenir paper goods, including photographs of scenic views on college campuses throughout Washington, Oregon, and Idaho. Many of these images were printed as post cards to be sold at the Universities. Today, the Company produces goods for the tourist and attraction industries including post cards and children's outdoor clothing.
The Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College consist of images of campus buildings and sorority and fraternity houses. These images were produced around 1955. Buildings and other views pictured include, but are not limited to, the chemical engineering building (Gleeson Hall), Dearborn Hall, the Library (Kidder Hall), the Women's Building, and the gates of the east campus entrance. A number of cooperative houses are also pictured. The Collection also contains images of 44 different fraternity and sorority houses. The majority of the collection consists of 5x7 negatives. A small number of prints are also included. One of the images is available online in the Best of the Archives digital collection. A link to the digitized image is available from the detailed image descriptions.
Collection is open for research.
The Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College is arranged in two series: I. Campus Buildings, circa 1955 - circa 1956 and II. Fraternity and Sorority Houses, circa 1955.
The negatives were sent to the OSU Bookstore in 1964 by Kyle S. Smith of the Smith-Western Co.
These photographs were donated to the University Archives in 1990 by David Nishitani, on behalf of the OSU Bookstore.
The OSU Memorabilia Collection contains information pertaining to campus buildings and the fraternities and sororities affiliated with Oregon State University. Additional photographs of campus buildings can be found in Harriet's Photograph Collection, News and Communications Services Photographs (P 057), the Buildings Photograph Collection (P 016), Gwil Evans Photograph Collection (P 082), and the OSU Historical Photographs (P 025). Campus building plans and blueprints are a part of the Facilities Services Records (RG 193). The Special Collections & Archives Research Center includes many collections documenting fraternities and sororities at Oregon State.
Oregon State College--Buildings.
Greek letter societies--Oregon--Corvallis.; College buildings--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student housing--Oregon--Corvallis.
Corvallis (Or.)
Photographic prints.; Film negatives.
Corvallis; Oregon; Photographs; Colleges and Universities
- Campus Buildings, circa 1955 - circa 1956; Series I; 25 negatives and 5 prints
  Series I consists of images of campus buildings and views. These include dormitories, cooperative houses, and the east campus entrance. This series consists mainly of 5x7 negatives, but also includes a few prints.
  - Azalea House, circa 1955; P164:01; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Chemical Engineering (Gleeson Hall), circa 1955; P164:02; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - OSC Coliseum, circa 1955; P164:03; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Co-op Cottage, circa 1956; P164:04; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
    Currently houses the administrative offices of the College of Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Sciences (Ocean Admin).
  - Davenport House, circa 1955; P164:05; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Dearborn Hall, circa 1955; P164:06; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Dearborn Hall entrance, circa 1955; P164:07; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - East campus entrance gate, circa 1956; P164:08; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - East campus entrance, circa 1956; P164:09; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - East campus entrance (education hall in background), 1956; P164:10; 5x7 negative and 2 prints (Box 1)
  - Home Economics building (Milam Hall), circa 1955; P164:11; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Food Technology Building (Weigand Hall), circa 1955; P164:12; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Heckart Lodge, circa 1955; P164:13; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Library entrance (Kidder Hall), circa 1955; P164:14; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Library (Kidder Hall), circa 1955; P164:15; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Library walk, circa 1955; P164:16; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Men's Dormitory (Weatherford Hall), circa 1955; P164:17; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Reed Lodge, circa 1955; P164:18; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sackett Hall, circa 1955; P164:19; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Waldo Hall (north side), circa 1955; P164:20; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - Waldo Hall (east side), circa 1955; P164:21; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Waldo Place and Campus Way intersection, Bexell and Gleeson Halls in background, circa 1955; P164:22; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Westminster House, circa 1955; P164:23; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Withycombe Hall, circa 1955; P164:24; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Women's Building entrance, circa 1955; P164:25; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
- Fraternity and Sorority Houses, circa 1955; Series II; 55 negatives and 4 prints
  Series II consists of images of sorority and fraternity houses. These images were produced around 1955 and consist mainly of 5x7 negatives.
  - Acacia Fraternity, circa 1955; P164:26; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Chi Omega, circa 1955; P164:27; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Delta Pi, circa 1955; P164:28; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Delta Pi, circa 1955; P164:29; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Gamma Delta, circa 1955; P164:30; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Gamma Rho, circa 1955; P164:31; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - Alpha Gamma Rho, circa 1955; P164:32; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi, circa 1955; P164:33; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi, circa 1955; P164:34; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi, circa 1955; P164:35; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi, circa 1955; P164:36; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Sigma Phi, circa 1955; P164:37; 3 negatives and print (Box 1)
  - Alpha Tau Omega, circa 1955; P164:38; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Xi Delta, circa 1955; P164:39; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Alpha Xi Delta, circa 1955; P164:40; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Chi Phi, circa 1955; P164:41; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Chi, circa 1955; P164:42; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Delta Delta, circa 1955; P164:43; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Gamma, circa 1955; P164:44; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Sigma Phi, circa 1955; P164:45; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Upsilon, circa 1955; P164:46; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Upsilon, circa 1955; P164:47; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Delta Zeta, circa 1955; P164:48; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta, circa 1955; P164:49; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Delta, circa 1955; P164:50; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Delta Rho, circa 1955; P164:51; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma, circa 1955; P164:52; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Sigma, circa 1955; P164:53; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Kappa Sigma, circa 1955; P164:54; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha, circa 1950; P164:55; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Delta Theta, circa 1955; P164:56; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Gamma Delta, circa 1955; P164:57; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa, circa 1955; P164:58; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, circa 1955; P164:59; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, circa 1955; P164:60; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Tau, circa 1955; P164:61; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Tau, circa 1955; P164:62; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Sigma Kappa, circa 1955; P164:63; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Pi Beta Phi, circa 1955; P164:64; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha, circa 1955; P164:65; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - Pi Kappa Phi, circa 1955; P164:66; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Pi Kappa Phi, circa 1955; P164:67; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Phi Kappa Psi, circa 1955; P164:68; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon, circa 1955; P164:69; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sigma Chi, circa 1955; P164:70; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sigma Kappa, circa 1955; P164:71; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sigma Nu, circa 1955; P164:72; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Sigma Pi, circa 1955; P164:73; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Tau Kappa Epsilon, circa 1955; P164:74; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Theta Chi, circa 1955; P164:75; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Theta Chi, circa 1955; P164:76; 5x7 negative (Box 1)
  - Gamma Phi Beta, circa 1955; P164:77; 5x7 negative and print (Box 1)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon, circa 1955; P164:78; 5x7 negative (Box 1)